> > 布莱恩: 我们会在这里做一种更先进的反应
&gt;&gt; Brian: So we're gonna do one more kind
of advance feature of react here which is
称为 " 门户网站" 。
called a Portal.
我们想让这个按钮在这里工作
We wanna make this button work here for
你点击的方式就是胖子 Slim cuz 是狗最棒的名字
the way you click adopt Fat boy Slim
cuz that's the greatest name for a dog.
所以你可以去收养她但我们想确保人们的感觉
So you can actually go and adopter her,
but we wanna make sure people are like,
你确定要收养这只宠物是个大问题
are you sure you wanna adopt
this cuz adopting a pet is a big
责任，对吧 ?
responsibility, right?
所以你想让每个人都喜欢斑纹
So you wanna pop up a mottle
cuz everyone loves mottles.
我讨厌飞毛虫但我要教你怎么做 motles，对
I hate mottles, but I'm gonna show
you how to make mottles, right.
所以，一瓶瓶子在你的屏幕上出现了一些类似的东西，
So, a mottle is something that pops over
your screen and says something like,
你确定你要这么做对吧
are you sure you want to do this, right?
这是我们一直在为自己做的很烦人的设计模式。
It's a really annoying design pattern
that we keep doing to ourselves.
我要用你的方式来延续这个模式
And I'm perpetuating the pattern
by showing you, yeah?
>> 演讲者 2: 如果你讨厌 ttle ，更好的选择是什么 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: If you hate mottles,
what is the better alternative?
>> Brian: 就像在线确认中一样，我不知道。
&gt;&gt; Brian: Just like in line confirmations,
I don't know.
我觉得要有更好的设计模式
I think there's better design
patterns to lean on than,
好像在我看来只是个懒惰的模式
like it's just kind of a lazy
pattern in my opinion.
警报，我只是开玩笑，这只是个玩笑。
Alerts, no I'm just kidding,
that's a joke.
是的，我不知道.
[LAUGH] Yeah, I don't know.
我得考虑更多的事但我觉得还有更好的办法
I'd have to think more about it,
but I think there's better ways.
> > 布莱恩: 所以，我想在这里做的事情就是这样。
&gt;&gt; Brian: So, the thing that I
wanna accomplish here, is that.
我有这个细节页面，对，我想点点胖子 Slim ，
I have this details page, right, and
I wanna click Adopt Fat Boy Slim and
我想把它弹出来，一个覆盖整个页面的模型，对吧 ?
I want it to pop over,
a model that covers the whole page, right?
这将非常困难，因为这已经嵌套在多层中
Now that would be really hard because this
is already nested within several layers
标记。
of markup.
所以在整个网页上都可能不可能
So taking over the whole
page might not be possible,
给生活在上面的 CSS 提供的信息
given the CSS that lives above it.
那你是怎么做到的
So, how do you do that?
这并不是一个很好的方法。
There's not really a good way of doing it.
如果你看我在这里的标记，我就在这里。
It'd be much better, if you look at my
markup here, I have root right here.
如果上面有一个模型，我就会很酷，我可以把它变成，对。
It'd be cool if there was a model above
it, that I could render into, right.
所以我们要用入口来做
And so, we're gonna do that with portals.
所以我想让你打开你的 index.html 文件
So, what I want you to do is I want
you to open your index.html file,
在源目录的内部，然后在根之上，
inside of the source directory,
and then above root,
将 #modal 置于其中的任何内容中。
put #modal with nothing in it.
所以一旦你做到了第 11 行
So once you've done that, line 11 there,
我希望您创建一个名为 Modal.js ， Modal.js 的新文件。
I want you to make a new file
called Modal.js, Modal.js.
你要去进口雷法和
And you go into import, React and
useEffect 和 useRef。
useEffect and useRef.
我们将在第二次，从 React中讨论 useRef 在这里的情况。
We'll talk about what useRef is
here in just a second, from React.
我想让你从反应界进口 createPortal 。
And that I want you to import
createPortal from react-dom.
> > Brian: 我想说， const modalRoot
&gt;&gt; Brian: I wanna say, const modalRoot
= document.getElementById 模态。
= document.getElementById modal.
然后我就会说，我们的模式是儿童的一种功能。
And then here, I'm gonna say, const modal
= a function which takes in children.
>> Brian: 并返回， >> Brian: 函数，
&gt;&gt; Brian: And returns,
&gt;&gt; Brian: Function,
> > 布莱恩: 所以我要用一个
&gt;&gt; Brian: So I'm gonna use a thing
这里叫 refs ，所以我要说 const elRef = useRef，
called refs here, so
I'm gonna say const elRef = useRef, and
我现在就给它空空
I'm gonna give it null for now.
所以 useRef是个有趣的事情
So useRef, it's an interesting thing.
所以我要创造一个我要创造的元素
So I'm gonna have this element
that I'm going to create,
我想经常提到同一个要素，对。
and I want to always refer
to the same element, right.
因为，当我创建模态的时候，我将会创建标记和
Because, when I create a modal,
I'm gonna be creating markup and
当我毁了它的时候对吧
when I destroy the modal, right.
还，我一下来，就得回去销毁了，
It's still, as soon as I pop down the
modal, I need to go back and destroy it,
好吧我得去把它解开
right, and I need to go un-render it.
如果我不破坏它我就会泄露内存
Because if I don't destroy it,
then I'm gonna leak memory if I open and
一帮不开放的时代
unopen modals a bunch of times.
我只会继续创造标记而不是毁掉它
I'm just gonna keep creating markup and
not destroying it.
所以你得在这里清理自己的垃圾我想说的是
So you kinda have to clean your own
garbage here, is what I'm saying.
useRef 允许您这样做。
And useRef allows you to do that.
因为你已经投降投降了
Because you have renders and re-renders,
您需要在呈现中引用相同的 dom 元素，对吗 ?
you need to refer to the same dom
elements across renders, right?
所以我不能只说，我不能在这里创造一个 DOM 元素。
So I can't just say, I can't just
create the DOM element in here const.
我说的时候 const div =
When I say, const div =
documents.createElements， div， right?
documents.createElements, div, right?
这将会每一次创建一个新的 div ，并且
So this would be creating a new
div every single time, and
这就是我们想要的对吧
that's what we want, right?
我们要一次创建一个 div 。
We want one div created once.
所以我们想说的是
So we're gonna say, here is going to say,
如果 elref.current。
if elref.current.
如果我没有 elref ，请创建 div 。
If I don't have an elref, create a div.
然后说， elRef.current = div .
And then say, elRef.current = div.
现在，我用这个钩子，我总是要有一个 div，对吧 ?
Now, I have using this hook,
I always I'm going to have a div, right?
正确的 div是相同的 div，因为 elRef 是对象，并且
A correct div, the same div,
because elRef is an object and
这个电流总是指向这个区的
this .current is always going
to be pointing at this div.
有道理吗
So makes sense?
> > 布莱恩: 好的，然后我在这里使用效果。
&gt;&gt; Brian: Okay, and
then I'm gonna use effect here.
UseEffect，因此第一次呈现时，
UseEffect, so once this renders for
the first time,
布莱恩: 我要说，
&gt;&gt; Brian: I'm gonna say,
modalRoot.appendChild， elRef.current.
modalRoot.appendChild, elRef.current.
事实上你能在这里做什么
And actually, what you could even do here?
你可以把它搬来这里
You could actually just move this in here.
这样你就不用待在这里了
Just so
you don't even have to be out here.
因此，仅在此处使用效果的模型根，而不是使用效果。
So instead of use effect, just say model
root inside of the use effect here.
AppendChild.elRef.current，所以我创建了这个 div，对吧 ?
AppendChild.elRef.current, so,
I created this div, right?
这将会在这里发生
And this is gonna go inside of here.
> > 布莱恩: 然后在这里，我想说回来。
&gt;&gt; Brian: And then here,
I wanna say return.
因此，使用具有我已告诉过您的特殊功能的效果。
So, use effect that has special feature
that I have been told you about.
如果返回是清除功能的功能。
If you return the function
that is the cleanup function.
它会在卸载过程中运行，对吗 ?
So it'll run this when it unmounts, right?
此组件将卸装挂钩。
This is component will unmount of hooks.
所以如果我能恢复一个在它最后的功能
So, if I return a function that,
at the end of it,
将会说， modalRoot.removeChild
will say, modalRoot.removeChild
elRef.current >> Brian: 因此
elRef.current
&gt;&gt; Brian: So
仅当模态根关闭时，才会运行此函数。
it's only going to run this function
whenever the modal root gets closed.
有道理吗
Does that make sense?
> > 布莱恩: 好的，然后在下面我们会说回来， createPortal，
&gt;&gt; Brian: Okay, and then down here
we're gonna say return, createPortal,
> > Brian: div，我们将全部打包
&gt;&gt; Brian: div, we're gonna wrap it all in
div孩子们
div, children.
>> Brian: 和 elref.current。
&gt;&gt; Brian: And elref.current.
我又要把一个二夫子带回来的原因是我用一个 div 的方式给它做了造型，就这样了。
The reason why I'm wrapping a div, again,
is cuz I styled it with a div, that's all.
然后在底部出口缺省的莫达尔
And then down at the bottom,
export default Modal.
>> 布莱恩: 这样，就能让这个模式的整个生命周期重新开始。
&gt;&gt; Brian: So, just to kinda recap
the whole life cycle of this modal.
顺便说下另一件事
The other thing, by the way,
我不想在这里做你该做的事
that I'm not doing here that you
should do if you're gonna do a modal.
我认为我最大的抱怨是他们无法获得
I think one of my biggest complaints about
modal as well is they're not accessible,
而且很难让他们接触
and they're hard to make accessible.
你必须把焦点放在 Cuz 上，捕捉焦点并不容易。
Cuz you have to trap focus, and
trapping focus is not easy all the time.
我们在这里不做的是捕捉焦点。
And what we're not doing
here is trapping focus.
所以我不知道怎么用我的头来给你展示如何
So, I don't know how to do it well enough
off the top of my head to show you how to
做，只是 google 如何把焦点集中在模态下，
do, it but just google how to
trap focus in a modal, and
你会比我更聪明的人
you'll have a lot more smart
people than me doing it.
> > 布莱恩: 所以我想说的是我们在这里
&gt;&gt; Brian: So what I wanna say
here is we grab the modal here,
是我们创造的那个身份证对吧
that ID one that we created, right?
那我们就追加这个 div ，对吧 ?
Then we append this div, right?
在 div的内部
And inside of the div,
我们会有所有的孩子， >> 布莱恩: 对吧 ?
we're gonna have all the children,
&gt;&gt; Brian: Right?
这就是我们在这里追加孩子的地方
That's where we'll do
the append child here, and
最后我们会把它移走
then at the end, we'll remove it.
但凉爽的部分就好像是被变成另一个部分，对，
But the cool part is like this is actually
getting rendered to another part, right,
使用此创建门户网站功能。
using this create portal function.
这将被呈现给 DOM 的不同部分
This is getting rendered to
a different part of the DOM, and
一旦它被卸载了我就会被拆去
then once it gets unmounted I'll
get room unmounted for that.
但酷的是我能用所有状态
But what's cool is like,
I can use all of the state and
将其呈示为另一部分，然后使用相同功能将其取消呈示。
render that into a different part and then
unrender it later using the same function.
>> 布莱恩: 到目前为止 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian: Follow me so far?
好了我们去做这个工作吧我要你去详细的
All right, let's go make this work,
I want you to go into details.js.
>> 布莱恩: 我们不做的一件事就是如果我们
&gt;&gt; Brian: One thing we didn't do that
would have been a disaster if we
没定吗
hadn't fixed?
我们希望这种效果多久才能运行 ?
How often do we want this effect to run?
> > 布莱恩:
&gt;&gt; Brian: Once right?
那么，我们如何实现一次有效的效果 ?
So how do we make an effect run once?
逗号，空数组。
Comma, empty array.
这没有依赖性，因此我们希望它运行一次。
This has no dependencies so
we want it to run once.
否则，每次在此更新子代时，这些都不是 true。
Otherwise every time that the children
get updated here, that's not true.
这个帖子会好起来的
This post would have been okay,
因为这里没有状态会随着时间的推移而改变
because there's this has no
state that's changing over time.
但我们还想再跑一次
But even still we only wanted to run once.
这可能是未来潜在的错误来源。
That that would have could have been
a potential future source of bugs.